Guide to the Frances Hesselbein Papers, 1942-2013 AIS.2013.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Frances Hesselbein Personal Papers, ca. 1930s-1940s, 1955-2014; B.
  - Speeches, 1976-2013; VII.
    - Hesselbein speeches, 1976-1987; 1.
      - Speeches, 1995
        - "The Powerful Third Force: Emergence of Non Profits"/"Social Sector Organizations: The Future of America" - Sacramento Association of Community Based Organizations, June 27, 1995; 18.
        - "Meeting the Challenge of Accountability" - Self-Assessment Tool Session, June 29, 1995; 19.
        - The Mennonite Church Extension Fund, September 29, 1995; 1. (Box 26, Folder 14)
        - "Common Concerns of the Social Sector" - Grantmakers of Western Pennsylvania, October 25, 1995; 2.
        - "The Social Sector: The Great Hope for the Future" - Canadian Drucker Award speech, October 26, 1995; 3.
        - Association of Volunteer Administration, October 28, 1995; 4.
        - Serving Customers, Changing Lives conference, October 31, 1995; 5.
        - Lane W. Adams Award for Excellence - American Cancer Society, November 11, 1995; 6.
        - Leadership California, November 14, 1995; 7.
        - CVO/CPO Exchange: Building and Effective Partnership - United Way, November 27, 1995; 8.
        - AARP Dialogue Preface, December 19, 1995; 9.
      - Speeches, 1996
        - Speech schedule, 1996; 1. (Box 26, Folder 15)
        - United Way, January 23, 1996; 2.
        - "A Perspective -- The Role and Working of the Voluntary Sector" - Ditchley Foundation Conference, February 6, 1996; 3.
        - Council on Foundation's Family Conference, February 8, 1996; 4.
        - "A Perspective -- The Role and Working of the Voluntary Sector", February 9, 1996; 5.
        - Keynote address - Greater Birmingham Foundation, March 4, 1996; 6.
        - Arizona State University reception, March 13, 1996; 7.
        - Arizona Business Breakfast, March 14, 1996; 8.
        - Worlds Award Luncheon - Arizona-Cactus Pine Girl Scout Council, March 14, 1996; 9.
        - Points of Light Summit Conference on Citizen Engagement and Community Restoration, March 21, 1996; 10.
        - American Women's Economic Development Corporation, March 23, 1996; 11.
        - AARP Membership Team, April 10, 1996; 12.
        - "The Social Sector: The New Significance" - The World Society of Association Executives, April 23, 1996; 13.
        - Non-For-Profit Entrepreneurial Leadership Conference, May 3, 1996; 14.
        - Carroll College Commencement speech, May 9, 1996; 15.
        - Fairleigh Dickinson University, May 17, 1996; 16.
        - Argentina Welcome Speech, May 29, 1996; 17.
        - "Ten Steps to Transformation" - The Organization of the Future, May 29, 1996; 18.
        - Speech to United Way Business Leaders, June 5, 1996; 1. (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - Speech to Office of Personnel Management, June 6, 1996; 2.
        - National Community Service Conference, June 9, 1996; 3.
        - National Society Fund Raising Executives, June 14, 1996; 4.
        - Norman Vincent Peale Award for Positive Thinking (for Bill Pollard), June 17, 1996; 5.
        - American Federation for Aging Research Board Retreat, June 21, 1996; 6.
        - Speech to International Opera Guild, July 12, 1996; 7.
        - Speech to National Association of College and University Business Officers, July 22, 1996; 8.
        - Aspen Institute Seminar, August 1996; 9.
        - "Skills of the Successful CEO in the 21st Century" - Drug and Alcohol Service Providers Organization of Pennsylvania, September 10, 1996; 10.
        - Speech to March of Dimes, September 13, 1996; 11.
        - Women's Health Symposium, October 2, 1996; 12.
        - Kodak Women Managers Leadership Development Program, October 3, 1996; 13.
        - Dinner speech for Kodak Women Managers Leadership Development Program, October 3, 1996; 14.
        - The National Council of Negro Women's Leadership Luncheon, October 10, 1996; 15.
        - Linkage Leadership Conference, October 16, 1996; 1. (Box 26, Folder 17)
        - "Women in Leadership: Changing the Corporate Culture" - New Women, New Leadership symposium, October 25, 1996; 2.
        - Beyond the Walls: Partnerships for a Better Future luncheon, November 1, 1996; 3.
        - International Philanthropy Day speech, November 12, 1996; 4.
        - Speech to The Community Foundation of Santa Clara, November 15, 1996; 5.
        - Hawaii's National Philanthropy Day speech, November 22, 1996; 6.
        - "Emerging Partnerships: New Ways for a New World", December 2, 1996; 7.
        - Speech to National Board of Trustees, December 6, 1996; 8.
        - United Way of Executive Partnerships, December 9, 1996; 9.
        - Speech to Manhattanville College Board of Directors, December 13, 1996; 10.
      - Speeches, 1997
        - "Cross-Sector Partnerships for Healthy Communities" - Nonprofit Center of Milwaukee, Inc., January 9, 1997; 1. (Box 26, Folder 18)
        - "Ministry and Leadership in Changing Times" - American Association of Pastoral Counselors, January 17, 1997; 2.
        - "New Challenges, New Opportunities, New Worlds" - Fundraising Day for Women in Financial Development, February 3, 1997; 3.
        - Speech to Edison Electric Institute, February 25, 1997; 4.
        - Speech to De Pree Leadership Center, March 3, 1997; 1. (Box 26, Folder 19)
        - Speech to American Society of Association Executives, March 11, 1997; 2.
        - Southwest CEO Leadership Award speech, March 13, 1997; 3.
        - National Council for International Visitors National Conference speech, April 6, 1997; 4.
        - "Nonprofit Institutions in the Next Millennium", April 15, 1997; 1. (Box 26, Folder 20)
        - 10th Annual Hunter Conference speech, May 15, 1997; 2.
        - Learning Center Carriage House speech, May 21, 1997; 3.
        - Breakout Session - Dartmouth Hitchcock Medical Center, June 13, 1997; 4.
        - Dartmouth Hitchcock Medical Center speech, June 13, 1997; 5.
        - Rotary Club of Americus, June 24, 1997; 6.
        - Speech to Habitat for Humanity, June 24, 1997; 1. (Box 26, Folder 21)
        - Speech to March of Dimes, June 26,1997; 2.
        - Speech at Georgia Southwestern University, June 26, 1997; 3.
        - "When Planning and Leading are Synonymous" - Society for College and University Planning conference, July 14, 1997; 4.
        - International Congress of Oral Implantologists World Congress speech, August 14, 1997; 5.
        - "When Planning and Leading are Synonymous" - Swedish Red Cross, August 1997; 1. (Box 26, Folder 22)
        - "Journey to Transformation" - Swedish Red Cross, August 29, 1997; 2.
      - Speeches, 1997
        - "Journey to Transformation" - Church of Nazarene, September 12, 1997; 1. (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Speech to New York Human Resource Planners, September 1997; 2.
        - "Managing Diversity: Shaping the Future" - Society for Human Resource Management, October 8, 1997; 3.
        - "Mission 2" speech, October 9, 1997; 4.
        - Speech to Polytechnic University, October 13, 1997; 1. (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - "Our Mission", October 13, 1997; 2.
        - "The Future Calls", October 1997; 3.
        - "The How to Be a Leader" - Crossroads, October 29, 1997; 4.
        - "Leaders in the 21st Century" - Leadership California, November 4, 1997; 5.
        - "Leadership in the Nonprofit Organization of the Future" - Urban League, November 12, 1997; 1. (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - "The Language of Leadership" (Original) - The New School, November 18, 1997; 2.
        - "The Language of Leadership" (Revised) - The New School, November 18, 1997; 3.
        - Peru 2021 speech, December 1, 1997; 1. (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - "Ethical Principles for Executives", December 3, 1997; 2.
        - United Way, December 9, 1997; 3.
        - Speech to Virginia Foundation for Women, December 11, 1997; 4.
      - Speeches, 1998
        - "Managing the Dream" - American Humanics Management Institute, January 2, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Welcome remarks - Philippines, January 21, 1998; 2a.
        - Philippines (Main Speech), January 21, 1998; 2b.
        - "What Business Can Learn from Nonprofits" - Innovative Thinking Conference 8, February 1998; 3.
        - "Governance in the New Millennium" - Premier's Annual Governance Education Conference, February 4, 1998; 4.
        - Mutual of America reception speech, February 11, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Conference Board speech, February 19, 1998; 2.
        - Conference Board speech 2, February 20, 1998; 3.
        - Human Resource Management - International Red Cross and Red Crescent Society, March 9, 1998; 4.
        - Geneva: Human Resources speech, March 10, 1998; 5.
        - "Leadership Imperatives for a New Century" (Original) - United Way of the Piedmont, March 10, 1998; 1a. (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - "Leadership Imperatives for a New Century" (Revised) - United Way of the Piedmont, March 10, 1998; 1b.
        - "Partners in a New World" - Olivet College, March 25, 1998; 2.
        - "Leadership and Beyond the Walls" - United Way of Canada annual conference, March 29, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - "Maintaining a Commitment to Community: Challenges facing the Not-For-Profit Sector", April 1, 1998; 2.
        - "The Future Calls" - The Peter F. Drucker Graduate School of Management, April 6, 1998; 3.
        - Eastern College speech, April 13, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - "Leadership in the New Millennium", April 22, 1998; 2.
        - "Good Government: A World of Ideas", April 22, 1998; 3.
        - Morning speech (Original) - Lutheran Services in America, April 23, 1998; 4.
        - Morning speech (Revised) - Lutheran Services in America, April 23, 1998; 5.
        - Speech to the Indiana Humanities Council, April 27, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - "Leadership for Optimal Organizational Performance" - University of Minnesota, May 14, 1998; 2.
        - Peter Drucker Archives Dedication speech, May 15, 1998; 3.
        - Speech to The Washington Center, May 20, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - Speech to National Head Start Association, June 2, 1998; 2.
        - "Introduction: The Context" - World Bank, June 18, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - "The World Bank in a World of Ideas" - World Bank, June 18, 1998; 2.
        - "Journey to Transformation" - World Bank, June 18, 1998; 3.
        - Speech to Universalist Assembly, June 27, 1998; 4.
        - Robert Wood Johnson Executive Nursing Fellows Seminar speech, July 26, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 13)
        - "Leadership and Volunteerism - And the Future of Organizations" - National Council of Bar Foundations speech, July 31, 1998; 2.
        - U.S. Army Consultation speech, August 12, 1998; 3.
        - Monadnock Summer Lyceum speech, August 16, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 14)
        - "Journey to Transformation", September 8, 1998
        - St. Vincent de Paul speech, September 8, 1998; 2.
        - Speech to American Institute of Architects, September 10, 1998; 3.
        - Speech to National Association of Homes and Services for Children, September 18, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 15)
        - "The Nature and Quality of Leadership" - Bates College, September 20, 1998; 2.
        - "The Role of the Board in Setting Strategic Direction: Segment I" - International Youth Foundation, October 2, 1998; 3.
        - "The Role of the Board in Fostering a Learning Organization: Segment II" - International Youth Foundation, October 2, 1998; 4.
        - "Fund-Raising and Fund-Development: Segment III" - International Youth Foundation, October 2, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 16)
        - Arkansas Hospital Association speech, October 5, 1998; 2.
        - Speech to Chicago Leadership symposium, October 13, 1998; 3.
        - World Food Prize speech, October 15, 1998; 4.
        - "Trends in the American Social Sector" - National Executive Service Corps, October 20, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 17)
        - Community Foundation speech, October 21, 1998; 2.
        - "Leadership in the 21st Century" - The American Institute of Architects, November 1, 1998; 3.
        - "Diversity" - World Bank, November 4, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 18)
        - "An Adventure in Organizational Self-Discovery" - Self Assessment Tool Launch, November 10, 1998; 2.
        - "Beyond the Walls: Partnerships for a Better Future" - University for Economic Affairs, November 25, 1998; 3.
        - "The Leader of the Future" - University of Richmond, December 2, 1998; 1. (Box 27, Folder 19)
        - "Celebrating Ourselves as Remarkable Women" - Virginia Foundation for Women, December 3, 1998; 2.
        - Drucker Foundation Holiday Party remarks, December 17, 1998; 3.
      - Speeches, 1999
        - "Women in the Next Millennium: Leadership Imperatives" - Arizona Women's Forum, March 3, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - "Leadership in the 21st Century: The Role of the Nonprofit Sector" - Arizona State University, March 4, 1999; 2.
        - "An Adventure in Organizational Self-Discovery" - Motorola University, March 5, 1999; 3.
        - "An Adventure in Organizational Self-Discovery" - United Way of the Piedmont, March 11, 1999; 4.
        - "Women in the Next Millennium: Leadership Imperatives" - Leadership America, March 14, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - "Nonprofit Charities: Their Role in the New Millennium" - The Salvation Army, March 25, 1999; 2.
        - "Leadership in a World of Change" - Australian Forum for Nonprofit Leadership and Management, April 14,1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - "Organizational Leadership in the 21st Century" - Interaction, April 26, 1999; 2.
        - "Leadership, Creativity and Character" - Center for Strategic and International Studies, April 29, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Speech to The Pennsylvania Society, May 7, 1999; 2.
        - "The Leader of the Future" - Thiel College Commencement, May 9, 1999; 3.
        - "The Community of the Future" - United States Army War College Commandant's Lecture Series, May 25, 1999; 4.
        - "Leadership Imperatives for the New Century" - Volunteer Jacksonville, June 4, 1999; 2. (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - "Journey to Transformation", June 7, 1999; 3.
        - "The Power of Leading by Voice" - Linkage: Women in Leadership, June 17, 1999; 4.
        - "Organizational Leadership in the 21st Century" - Society for Organizational Learning, June 28, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - "Celebrating Leaders Who Are Women" - Women of the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America, July 10, 1999; 2.
        - Ducker Foundation Fellows Reception and Leading Beyond the Walls Book Party remarks, September 24, 1999; 3.
        - "The Power of Leading By Voice" - Richmond Women's Club, October 4, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - "The Power of Leading By Voice" - Service Master, October 6, 1999; 2.
        - "Journey to Transformation" - University of Michigan, October 12, 1999; 3.
        - Junior Achievement Leadership Academy speech, October 18, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Mexico City speech, November 1999; 2.
        - Speech to United Way - Women's Leadership Council of San Antonio and Bexar County, November 10, 1999; 1. (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - "An Adventure in Organizational Self-Discovery" - Mexico City Self-Assessment Tool Session speech, November 29, 1999; 2.
        - Junior Achievement Leadership Academy speech, December 1999; 3.
        - "The Role of the Board in Setting Strategic Direction: Segment I" - SUNY New Paltz Foundation, December 2, 1999; 4.
        - California Transportation Training Institute - California Emergency Foodlink graduation speech, December 22, 1999; 5.
      - Speeches, 2000
        - "Challenges of Leadership in the New Century" - Drucker-JAIMS Inaugural Roundtable, January 12, 2000; 1. (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - The Collaboration Challenge Book Reception speech, February 16, 2000; 2.
        - "Leader to Leader", March 22, 2000; 3.
        - "Leadership Transition", April 6, 2000; 4.
        - Speech to Layette College Women's Association, April 7, 2000; 1. (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Speech to Women's Association of Lafayette College, April 10, 2000; 2.
        - Speech to Danish Management Association, April 13, 2000; 3.
        - "Collaboration Among Public Agencies - An Innovative Model for the 21st Century", April 19, 2000; 4.
        - California Transportation Training Institute graduation speech, August 25, 2000; 1. (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - National Meeting of the YMCA speech, September 2000; 2a.
        - "Address to Peter Jensen", September 15, 2000; 2b.
        - Biographical Excerpts, March, 2000-April, 2000
        - "Leading of the Organization and Community of the Future" - Catholic Charities of USA, September 29, 2000; 3.
        - Andersen Consulting speech, October 13, 2000; 1. (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - Birmingham-Southern College speech, October 17, 2000; 2.
        - "The Challenge of the Sigmoid Curves" - Alabama Power Company Management Council, October 18, 2000; 3.
        - Speech to International Leadership Association of Toronto, Canada, November 4, 2000; 4.
        - "One in a Million" - Capital Grounds, November 17, 2000; 1. (Box 28, Folder 14)
        - Church Pensions Conference speech, November-December 2000; 2.
        - Speech to the American Lung Association, December 2, 2000; 1. (Box 28, Folder 15)
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls" - Claremont University, December 6, 2000; 2.
        - National Association of Attorneys General, 2000; 3.
      - Speeches, 2001
        - "The Power of Shared Achievement" - Junior Achievement, January 22, 2001; 1. (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - United States Army War College speech, January 2001; 2.
        - Management and Policy speech - National Summit Disney Institute Health Services, February 2001; 3.
        - "A Time for Leaders" - Claremont McKenna College, February 22, 2001; 4.
        - University of Pittsburgh Honors Convocation speech, February 28, 2001; 5.
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls" - The Smithsonian Institute at International Financial Corporation, March 13, 2001; 6.
        - "Leading in Turbulent Times" - University of St. Thomas, March 21, 2001; 7.
        - "Leadership Imperatives for Leadership Teams: Governance and Management in a New Decade" - Madison Community Foundation, March 22, 2001; 1. (Box 28, Folder 17)
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls" - President's Association of Canada, April 4, 2001; 2.
        - "Challenges of the Non-profit Century" - Lanterman Regional Center, April 7, 2001; 3.
        - Athena International Leadership Award Dinner acceptance speech, May 3, 2001; 4.
        - "Three Powerful Forces", May 4, 2001; 5.
      - Speeches, 2001
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls: Partnerships for a Better Tomorrow" - The University of St. Thomas, May 9, 2001; 1. (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Speech to Mile High United Way Chairmen's Forum on Community Leadership, May 14, 2001; 2.
        - El Pomar Foundation Nonprofit Leadership Conference speech, May 14, 2001; 3.
        - "Challenges of the Nonprofit Century" - The Ford Family Foundation Community Leadership Conference, May 16, 2001; 4.
        - "The Coast Guard: Transformation" - United States Coast Guard Senior Executive Leadership Conference, May 16, 2001; 1. (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - "Leader to Leader" - Michigan Nonprofit Association Grantmakers/Grantseekers, May 22, 2001; 2.
        - "Securing the Future: Resource Development for Nonprofits" - Twenty Fifth Hour Leadership Cincinnati, May 24, 2001; 3.
        - "Leading in Turbulent Times" - Friends of the Center Leadership Conference, May 30, 2001; 4.
        - "Journey to Transformation" - Head Start Network and Technical Training Seminar, June 15, 2001; 1. (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - "Journey to Transformation" - Women in Community Service, June 21, 2001; 2.
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls - Changing Lives and Building Communities" - Southern Region Program Leadership Committee meeting, July 11, 2001; 3.
        - Speech to Council of Alumni Association Executives, July 13, 2001; 4.
        - Collaboration Challenge Training Workshop speech, August 4, 2001; 5.
        - Speech to Pennsylvania State University, September 24, 2001; 6.
        - Speech to State of California Department of Corrections - Institutions Divisions, October 1, 2001; 7.
        - Charitable Trusts and Solicitations Seminars - Nonprofit Leadership Conference speech, October 9, 2001; 8.
        - National Association of State Charities Conference speech, October 25, 2001; 9.
        - Henry A. Rosso Lifetime Achievement Award response, October 2001; 10.
        - Business for Social Responsibility Conference speech, November 9, 2001; 1. (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Arizona Courage to Lead Conference speech, November 13, 2001; 2.
      - Speeches, 2002
        - "Women Make a Difference" - United Way of New Orleans, January 15, 2002; 1. (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - "Journey to Transformation" - Project Grad USA National Conference, January 22, 2002; 2.
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls: Building Partnerships for a Better Future" - Our Lady of the Lake University, February 7, 2002; 3.
        - Dynamic Women in Action Luncheon - Linking Education and Economic Development, March 18, 2002; 4.
        - Brandeis University speech, April 10, 2002; 5.
        - Brandeis University - Boston Club speech, April 11, 2002; 6.
        - National Leadership Dialogue - Kellogg Forum on Higher Education for the Public Good, May 9, 2002; 7.
        - Girl Scout Executive Staff National Conference speech, October 2002; 8.
        - Women's Leadership Initiative - United Way Lehigh Valley, November 22, 2002; 9.
      - Speeches, 2003
        - "The Art of Leadership in Public Health" - The Center for Disease Control and Public Health, February 20, 2003; 1. (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Testimony of Frances Hesselbein to Little Hoover Commission, February 27, 2003; 2.
        - Speech to North Georgia College, March 4, 2003; 3.
        - Speech to National Council of Jewish Women, March 8, 2003; 4.
        - Self-Assessment Tool speech to Banco Popular, March 15, 2003; 5.
        - "Making Waves for Change" - Women's Association of Verizon Employees, March 28, 2003; 6.
        - "Developing Leaders" - Goldman Sachs Global Leaders Program, April 10, 2003; 7.
        - Investment in America Forum speech, April 30, 2003; 8.
        - "A Time for Leaders" - ASTD International Conference and Expo, May 19, 2003; 9.
        - Beit Issie Shapiro Conference in Israel digital video conference speech, May 21, 2003; 10.
        - "Leveraging Through Improving Organizational Capacity" - Merrill Lynch and Princeton University, June 5, 2003; 11.
        - American Association of Retired Persons (AARP) speech, July 12, 2003; 12.
        - NY Talks speech, August 4, 2003; 13.
        - "A Time for Leaders" - League of California Cities, September 7, 2003; 14.
        - "Leading Beyond the Walls", September 19, 2003; 15.
        - "Authenticity and Leadership" - HR.com, October 28, 2003; 16.
        - "Nonprofit Organization in Changing Times" - Collaborative Alliance, November 12, 2003; 17.
        - Monday closing remarks - Volunteers of America Leadership Retreat, November 17, 2003; 18.
        - Speech to United Way of America, December 10, 2003; 19.
      - Speeches, 2004
        - ASAE Leadership Conference speech, January 28, 2004; 1. (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - La Verne University speech, February 12, 2004; 2.
        - California Performance Review, March 29, 2004; 3.
        - Women and Corporate and Nonprofit Governance Panel - MIT Sloan School of Management, April 1, 2004; 4.
        - "We Are Called" - Geneva College Annual Leadership Conference, April 7, 2004; 5.